CHRISTOPHER NEAL LEE

San Francisco, CA 94110

Phone: (415) 716-0375 | Email: christopher.neal.lee@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/christophernlee/ | GitHub: https://github.com/CofChips |

Portfolio: https://cofchips.github.io/professional_materials/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with extensive experience in Marketing and Strategy and a passion for self-improvement and continuous learning. Utilizes strong attention to detail and ability to translate high-level concepts into detailed actions to develop user-centric, responsive websites. Excels at approaching programming challenges from different perspectives and developing apps to help solve everyday problems. Proven leader who deals professionally with tension, time constraints, and conflicts to lead collaboratively through challenging issues or projects. MBA from Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (ranked 17th in the world). Bootcamp Certificate from UC Berkeley (Full Stack Web Development).

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript,

Libraries and Frameworks: jQuery, Bootstrap

Runtime Environments: Node.js

Others: SQL, MySQL, JSON, APIs, AJAX, GitHub, command line, writing tests

PROJECTS

Weather Dashboard | Repository: https://github.com/CofChips/weather_dashboard/ Live Site: https://cofchips.github.io/weather_dashboard/

- Weather app that displays real-time weather results and forecasts and stores user searches in local storage
- Lead developer responsible for all aspects of coding
- Built using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, OpenWeather API

Random Music Quiz | Repository: https://cofchips.github.io/code_quiz/#
Live Site: https://cofchips.github.io/code_quiz/#

- Quiz app with dynamically generated elements featuring a timer and a high score list that stores in local storage
- Lead developer responsible for all aspects of coding
- Built using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript

Work&Balance | Repository: https://github.io/JobSearchEateries/ Live Site: https://cofchips.github.io/JobSearchEateries/

- Job search app designed to enrich the job hunting process by displaying food and beverage establishments within 1500 meters of each hiring company's office
- Project Manager and Javascript developer responsible for all API queries
- Built using HTML5, CSS3, Foundation, Javascript, jQuery, toastr, GitHub Jobs API, Google Places API, Heroku CORS Anywhere

EXPERIENCE

San Francisco Bay Area Moms, LLC Co-owner

San Francisco, CA 2019 – Present

Co-owner of San Francisco Bay Area Moms, a collaborative website providing resources for Bay Area parents and a member of the City Mom Collective, the largest collection of hyper-local mom influencers in the US.

AXA	Hong Kong and Jakarta, Indonesia
Head of Marketing	2017 – 2019
Head of Strategy	2016 – 2017
Distribution Development Manager	2013 – 2016
Strategic Development Manager	2010 – 2013
Management Trainee	2009 – 2010

Held management and senior management roles across various functions for Paris-based global insurance company, AXA. Responsibilities ranged from overseeing the Marketing, Communications, CSR, and Strategy departments to end-to-end strategy development and implementation – from formulation, to identifying and executing actionable items.

Key Accomplishments:

- Increased Net Promoter Score, a metric used to evaluate customer satisfaction, +5 pts compared
 to market by developing an outreach program focused on improving the quality and frequency of
 online and offline engagement while leveraging exclusive partnerships to create a unique
 customer experience
- Increased revenue by approximately \$15m per annum by designing and implementing a business quality metric into compensation scorecards for life insurance brokers and independent financial advisors

Paychex, Inc. Technical Support Specialist

Costa Mesa, CA

2006 - 2007

Provided technical and update installation support for 1,500 customers throughout Southern California.

Able Software, Inc. Customer Service Representative, Level II

Irvine, CA

2004 - 2006

Provided technical support for customers worldwide.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

An intensive 12-week bootcamp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned included HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

MBA: Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong

Recipient of the Graduate School of Business Merit Scholarship. Admitted to the prestigious full-time program ranked 17th (3-year average) in the world by Financial Times.

BA, Chinese Language and Literature: University of California, Irvine, Irvine, CA